Emanuel Augusto Severino de Matos

Mobile: **☎** (5511) 979.920.222 - ☑ <u>emanuel@uol.com.br</u> - ⑤ emanuel.matos.07

Summary of Qualifications

Currently with over 8 years experiences in Information Systems, 12 years in Managing. Machine Learning, Clustering, Sampling, Ad Hoc Research, database, design, development, deployment and maintenance of KPIs are some experiences areas. Knowledge of Office package, Windows, SPSS, SAS, R, Minitab, MySQL, Crystal Reports, Hive, PIG and little experience in C++. Focus on results, versatility in decision making. Management experience in the branch Editorial, Graphic and Retal. In this branch with experience in: business plan, logistics, costs, budgets for strategic planning, new business development, mergers, acquisitions and ERP environment - SAP and Magnus.

Languages Known

- Portuguese Mother language
- English Professional working proficiency
- Spanish Elementary proficiency

Academic Background

- MSc in Data Analysis and Decision Support Systems Univ. Porto / Portugal 2010
- MBA in Business Administration IBMEC 2002
- Statistics Univ. Fed. of Sao Carlos 1990

Courses

- Summer School on Data Sciences for Big Data Resource Aware Data Mining Porto/Portugal 02/09/2015 05/09/2015
- KDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining - 08/2016 / San Franc. and 08/2014 / NYC
- Cloudera Data Analyst Training: Using Pig, Hive and Impala with Hadoop 03/12/2013 05/12/2013
- Advanced Topics in Management and Finance Universidad Carlos III de Madrid ES -09/2003
- Managing International Business University of Illinois, IL USA 06/2002
- Production Management and Competitive Operations -1998. Controlling 1995 / Fund. Getulio Vargas Brazil

Honors & Awards

- Magazine Exame/Brazil March/2016 Interview into career article "Nadando em Números"
- Walmart <code> 1st Place September / 2013 Solve complex problems in creative and have fun at the same time. Participant in the team which made a hub to centralize all communications with clients.

Professional Experience

Mandae Logistic Consulting (03/2018 – actual)

Data Scientist

I started into Mandaê to a challenge studying to create new design to freight rates/table based into IA. Reviewed routes from delivering and loading. Both issues with focus into increase into large scale and apply Machine Learning.

• Walmart ecommerce (05/2013 - 01/2018)

Marketing Specialist

I started looking for create a new vision, looking for more and huge insights. New definition from a local DBM to will explore deeper the relationship between CRM, Business, Supply Chain and IT areas. Applying concepts by Machine Learning into this task.

Senior Technology Analyst

Developing criteria for Clean Data on over 12M records of the Customers. Pre-processing unstructured data base of customers. Created and provided algorithmic techniques for product recommendations to customers and apply with machine learning/IA (create a mix with Random Forest/ Apriori / Filtering Collaboration) algorithmic. Machine was applied for windows shopping into main Web Site and emails to retargeting. The algorithm still learning itself were the customers bought or browsed into web site. Paralleling I used to create segmentation based of customer's purchasing / browsing and socio-demographic profile. Planed RFM classification. Studied and calculated LTV. Studied overall view about customer, from register until delivered. Nowadays I diving into growing Machine Learning into Catalog area based in Associated Rules/Text Mining. Clustering, Filtering collaboration, Random Forest, Associated Rules, Text Mining are some of Statistics Techniques used. R, Python, Mysql are some of tools used to created POC.

• The Group / Volkswagen (02/2012 - 04/2013)

Data Mining Specialist

Statistical Working as a team formed to meet the CRM Volkswagen, development targeting premium customers based on RFM and clustering, creation of demand forecasting models based solely on quantitative data.

Paulista - UNIP University (04/2011 - 07/2015)

Associate professor and Auxiliary Coordinator Course IT

Professor of Information Systems at Unit Marginal Pinheiros, distance education in the disciplines of Statistics, Applied Mathematics, Information Security, and Software Systems Free Internet. Co-author of the book Strategic Planning for IT.

• Editora Abril (12/2010 - 06/2011)

Statistics Consultant

Acting as Statistician, within the IT field, reviewing the entire database of ITSM tool T-System, measuring the performance of SLA systemss, making the quality control of information, development and implementation of KPIs, and Dashboards backlogs and disseminating knowledge with staff and partners.

Folha de S. Paulo – Newsprint (09/1990 – 01/2007) – Several Manager Positions